Fred Crawford Papers
Marist College
Fred Crawford Papers
1892 - 2008
Fred Crawford was Professor of English at Central Michigan University who researched Lowell Thomas for a biography from 1991 – 1998.
98 linear feet
Crawford, Fred
Marist College Archives & Special Collections James A. Cannavino Library 3399 North Road Poughkeepsie, NY 12601
The items in folders one through ten have no restrictions. All items in folder Eleven: Research Materials and Secondary Sources, have copyrights retained by the original authors or their descendants, as stipulated by United States copyright law http://www.loc.gov/copyright/title17/.
Fred Crawford was Professor of English at Central Michigan University who researched Lowell Thomas for a biography from 1991 – 1998.
Thomas, Lowell, 1892-1981; Crawford, Fred
The Fred Crawford Papers consists of the research material gathered by Central Michigan University Professor Fred Crawford from 1991 to 1998 for a biography on Lowell Thomas. Most of the material within the collection appears to have been maintained in an orderly fashion by Fred Crawford. The lone exception to this is Series 2 which may have been the material Crawford was currently working on as well as assorted on-hand and reference material. While the order within most of the file series was not maintained during the transport to Marist College, the original order was recreated during processing based on the detail of Crawford’s original folder descriptions. These descriptions were maintained when possible with alterations made only for consistency and completion. Misfiles that appeared to be organic were maintained to preserve as much of Crawford’s original and unique order as possible.
- 1. Original material from Lowell Thomas Papers
  - 1.1 Original material from Series 2, 1925 - 1960
    - Bibliography Checks (moved from Series 2: Administrative file), undated; 1.1.1.1 (Box 1)
    - Admirals Dinner, April 11, 1950; 1.2.1.2 (Box 1)
    - Address, 1930 - 1956; 1.2.1.3 (Box 1)
    - Order of Adventures, 1930 - 1964; 1.2.1.4 (Box 1)
    - Advertising Club, 1937 - 1974; 1.2.1.5 (Box 1)
    - Afghanistan Relief Committee, 1980; 1.2.1.6 (Box 1)
    - Age, 1944 - 1978; 1.2.1.7 (Box 1)
    - Akin hall Association, 1940 - 1971; 1.2.1.8 (Box 1)
    - Alaska, 1914 - 1917; 1.2.1.9 (Box 1)
    - Alaska, 1933 - 1981; 1.2.1.10 (Box 1)